export const chapter =
  "Chapter - 3: The Deccan and South India in Early Medieval Period  ";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "What geographical features historically separated North and South India?",
        optionA: "The Ganges River",
        optionB: "The Narmada River and the Vindhya Hills",
        optionC: "The Brahmaputra River",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "During which historical period did increased interaction occur between North and South India?",
        optionA: "Ancient period",
        optionB: "Early medieval period",
        optionC: "Modern period",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question: "Which dynasty was powerful in the Deccan region?",
        optionA: "Mauryas",
        optionB: "Rashtrakutas",
        optionC: "Cholas",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Rashtrakutas struggled with which dynasties for control over Kannauj?",
        optionA: "Guptas and Mauryas",
        optionB: "Palas and Pratiharas",
        optionC: "Mughals and Marathas",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Kailash Temple at Ellora and the rock-cut Elephanta Caves were constructed during the time of which dynasty?",
        optionA: "Cholas",
        optionB: "Rashtrakutas",
        optionC: "Pallavas",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which dynasty ruled the region between the Narmada and Godavari rivers in the twelfth century?",
        optionA: "Vadavas",
        optionB: "Chalukyas",
        optionC: "Kakatiyas",
        correctAnswer: "A",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which dynasty ruled the territories between the Godavari and Krishna rivers in the twelfth and thirteenth centuries?",
        optionA: "Vadavas",
        optionB: "Chalukyas",
        optionC: "Kakatiyas",
        correctAnswer: "C",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The three important dynasties in South India were the Pallavas, the Pandyas, and the _______?",
        optionA: "Guptas",
        optionB: "Chalukyas",
        optionC: "Cholas",
        correctAnswer: "C",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Who is credited with founding the town of Mahabalipuram and constructing the Ratha temples?",
        optionA: "Rajaraja Chola",
        optionB: "Narsimhavarman",
        optionC: "Parantaka",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which philosophy, based on selfless love for God and kindness for fellow beings, emerged during this time?",
        optionA: "Bhakti",
        optionB: "Advaita",
        optionC: "Lingayat",
        correctAnswer: "A",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blanks:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "The Narmada River and the Vindhya Hills in central India have been traditional boundaries between _______ and South India.",
        optionA: "East",
        optionB: "North",
        optionC: "West",
        correctAnswer: "North",
      },
      {
        question:
          "During the early medieval period, the rulers of both North India and South India wanted to expand their influence, which led to increased _______.",
        optionA: "warfare",
        optionB: "isolation",
        optionC: "interaction",
        correctAnswer: "interaction",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The area between the Narmada and the Krishna rivers is known as the _______.",
        optionA: "Deccan",
        optionB: "Himalayas",
        optionC: "Gangetic Plain",
        correctAnswer: "Deccan",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Rashtrakutas were very powerful in the region of the _______.",
        optionA: "Ganges Valley",
        optionB: "Deccan",
        optionC: "Eastern Ghats",
        correctAnswer: "Deccan",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Rashtrakutas struggled with the Palas and the Pratiharas for control over _______.",
        optionA: "Delhi",
        optionB: "Kannauj",
        optionC: "Varanasi",
        correctAnswer: "Kannauj",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The famous Kailash Temple at Ellora and the rock-cut Elephanta Caves were constructed during the time of the _______.",
        optionA: "Cholas",
        optionB: "Rashtrakutas",
        optionC: "Pallavas",
        correctAnswer: "Rashtrakutas",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The region between the Narmada and Godavari rivers was ruled by the _______ dynasty in the twelfth century.",
        optionA: "Vadavas",
        optionB: "Chalukyas",
        optionC: "Marathas",
        correctAnswer: "Vadavas",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The three important dynasties that ruled South India included the Pallavas, the Pandyas, and the _______.",
        optionA: "Guptas",
        optionB: "Chalukyas",
        optionC: "Cholas",
        correctAnswer: "Cholas",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Narsimhavarman founded the town of Mahabalipuram and constructed the _______ temples.",
        optionA: "Sun Temple",
        optionB: "Ratha",
        optionC: "Lotus Temple",
        correctAnswer: "Ratha",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which philosophy, based on selfless love for God and kindness for fellow beings, emerged during this time?",
        optionA: "Bhakti",
        optionB: "Advaita",
        optionC: "Lingayat",
        correctAnswer: "Bhakti",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "The Narmada River and the Vindhya Hills served as traditional boundaries between North and South India.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Rashtrakutas were the rulers of South India during the early medieval period.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Kailash Temple at Ellora and the rock-cut Elephanta Caves were constructed during the time of the Rashtrakutas.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Vadavas ruled the region between the Narmada and Godavari rivers in the twelfth century.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question: "The Pandyas defeated the Cholas in the ninth century.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Rashtrakutas struggled with the Palas and the Pratiharas for control over Delhi.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Indian rulers under the Subsidiary Alliance System were fully independent of British control.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Chola dynasty expanded its kingdom overseas by annexing Sri Lanka.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The British attacked Mysore with the help of the Nizam of Hyderabad in the Fourth Anglo-Mysore War in 1799.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The British claimed that their authority was inferior in India.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
